原创翻译  双语字幕
最新连载海外影视剧下载
请登陆 www.YYeTs.com
仅供交流学习  禁止商用盈利
《沼泽怪物》前情回顾
Previously on Swamp Thing...
是哈伦  他染上了那种病
It's Harlan. He's come down with the disease.
我要进霍兰的实验室
I need to get into Holland's lab
查出他到底在研究什么
and figure out what he was working on.
幸运的话  能指引我找到治愈方法
With any luck, it'll point me towards a cure.
实验室研究笔记
来吧  上都  拿出那些卡牌吧
Come on, Xanadu. Break out those cards.
再给我解读一次
Give me one more reading.
你来玛雷已经八年了
Eight years since you've come to Marais,
你的卡牌就没变过
and your cards never change.
这次是逆位
This time they're reversed.
是好事吗
Is that good?
你最近有新认识的人吗
Did someone new come into your life?
艾比·亚凯恩
Abby Arcane.
你觉得我要等的人就是她吗
Do you think she's the one I'm supposed to be waiting for?
伍德罗博士  他还需要最后一笔经费
Dr. Woodrue, he just needs one more tranche of funding.
你还需要更多我家的钱
You need more of my family's money.
我的回答是不
The answer is no.
你在干什么  玛丽亚
What are you doing, Maria?
你不能切断我的资金
You're not cutting me off!
我不明白为什么这种疾病要攻击我们
I don't understand this disease and why it's fighting us.
不是攻击
Not fighting.
是反击
Fighting back.
抗生素只会让情况恶化
The antibiotics are just making things worse.
医生  血压在下降
Doctor, the BP is dropping.
我知道你一直在
I know you've been making
秘密贷款给埃弗里·桑德兰
off-the-books loans to Avery Sunderland.
我不知道你以为自己挖到了什么料
I don't know what you think you've got,
但那完全是胡扯
but it's complete and utter bullshit.
你要瞒住那笔钱
You gotta cover for that missing money.
然后闭紧你的嘴巴
You're gonna keep your goddamn mouth shut.
或者我可以找媒体
Or I could just talk to the press and
告诉他们我了解的你和秘密会议的事
tell them what I know about you and the Conclave.
你这个蠢蛋
You dumb son of a bitch!
桑德兰地产
你还等什么呢  捅他
What are you waiting for? Shank him!
见鬼  埃弗里  快他妈过来
Damn it, Avery! Get your ass over here!
快把它砍死
Now open this bitch up!
快点  儿子
Come on, son!
我做不到
I can't.
我知道你能做到
I know you can.
看看它的眼睛
Look at its eyes.
死物的眼睛
Dead eyes.
沼泽的眼睛
Swamp eyes.
不值得丝毫的仁慈
Not worth a second of mercy.
丝毫的仁慈
A second of mercy.
快点  儿子
Come on, son!
快点
Come on!
废物
Worthless...
你说这里不会有蛇吧
You don't think there's, uh, snakes up there, do you?
到处都有蛇  孩子
There's snakes everywhere, kid.
昨天还有个蛇蝎心肠的人对我发飙
Had one yelling at me yesterday.
嚷嚷房贷的事
About a house payment.
在那边
In there.
看到了吗
You see 'em?
在棉白杨后面
Behind the cottonwoods.
这太棒了
This is sweet.
你知道想找一棵
You know how hard it is to find
不归大木材公司所有的柏树有多难吗
a stand of cypress that big timber hadn't pissed over first?
得往里走五十码才行
You gotta wait till you get 50 yards in.
咱们把这玩意砍了
We'll, uh... We'll cut through this little shit,
辟出通道
and, uh, make a path.
什么鬼
What the hell?
赫斯佩洛斯旅馆
211房间
停下
Stop!
它伤了我
It cut me!
这他妈是尸体
It's a fucking corpse!
快回船上去
Let's get back to the boat!
快点  那边
Come on! That way!
翻译  布塔
翻译  DustD
翻译  冰岛豆腐
翻译  小酸奶
翻译  SwampSide152
翻译  DerbyNinja
翻译  余欢
翻译  马丁马丁回音山
翻译  沼泽小鱼人
翻译  iLOST
翻译  Serrino
时间轴  紫夏
时间轴  西·查
校对  屯栗子
校对  布塔惊吓过度
后期  渔夫
字幕总监制  布塔
沼泽   怪物
第一季  第四集
戴尔瑞餐馆
抱歉  我迟到了
Sorry I'm late.
我昨晚在沼泽遇上了麻烦
I got caught up on the water last night.
巴特勒又拉你去奥科伊河道了
Butler dragging you around Ochee Forks again?
是啊
Yeah.
天黑后可不该去那地方
That place is nowhere to be after dark.
别担心
Don't worry.
我再也不会去那里了
I'm never going back there again.
该死的伤口
This damn cut!
怎么了
What's wrong?
我看到了什么
I saw something.
它在动
It was moving.
我没看到什么在动
I don't see anything movin'.
尤其是这些锅碗瓢盆  你懂我的意思
Especially not those pots and pans, if you catch my drift.
是的  女士
Yes, ma'am
莉兹  你整理好那些清洁用品了吗
Liz, you got those cleaning supplies sorted?
马上就好  老爸
Almost, Pops.
它咬了我
It bit me!
它咬了我  它咬了我
It bit me! It bit me!
陶德  怎么回事
Todd, what's going on?
-陶德  -是条该死的蛇
- Todd! - It's a goddamn snake!
陶德  陶德
Todd! Todd!
陶德  什么蛇
Todd! What snake?
陶德
Todd.
陶德  住手  那里什么都没有
Todd, stop, there's nothing there.
-陶德  -把它弄掉
- Todd! - Get it off me!
-把它弄掉  -把刀放下
- Get it off me! - Drop the knife!
-把它弄掉  -陶德  不要
- Get it off me! - Todd! No!
退后  退后
Back! Get back!
那里没有蛇
There's no snake!
陶德  不要
Todd! No!
你干了什么
What did you do?
陶德
Todd.
说句话
Talk to me.
天啊
God...
不不不  坚持住
No, no, no. Stay with me.
-陶德  -坚持住
- Todd. - Stay with me.
亚历克
Alec!
我是来帮你的  我不能留你一人在这里
I'm here to help you! I'm not leaving you here alone!
亚历克
Alec!
Alec?
亚历克  是你吗
Alec, is that you?
我想要搞清楚这一切
I want us to figure this out,
亚历克
Alec...
但我们必须同心协力
But we have to do it together.
我能采集一份组织样本吗  拜托了
Can I have a tissue sample? Please?
谢谢
Thank you.
告诉我我变成了什么
Tell me what I've become.
不管你发现什么
Whatever you find.
我会的
I will.
回来要小心
Be careful coming back.
这里有危险
There's danger here.
你到底怎么了  亚历克
What is happening to you, Alec?
你的数据里有个错误
You've made a mistake in your data.
什么
Excuse me?
这些数字
These numbers.
它们只适用于表示细胞壁的厚度
They can only refer to the thickness of a cell wall,
也就是说你记述的是植物
which means you're describing a plant.
但是细胞周边是弧形且不规则的
But the cell circumferences are round and irregular,
更像是能移动的东西
more suited to something with mobility.
所以要么是植物
So it's either a plant,
要么是动物
or an animal.
你选一个
Now pick one.
如果我说输入的数字是准确的呢
And what if I told you my entries are accurate?
过去一千万年的生物学不会同意
Well, the last ten million years of biology would disagree with you.
我也不会
As would I.
你想
Would you, uh...
你想让我看看吗
Would you like me to take a look?
好
Sure.
这...这是植物组织
Well, this is... This is plant tissue,
但是模式却像是动物组织
but it's organized like animal tissue.
不符合任何已知的动植物门类
It fits no known phylum.
我猜你
I assume that you, uh...
是在沼泽里找到这个的
found this in the swamp?
你打算怎么处理它
What are you, um, planning to do with it?
全面分析
Well, a full analysis.
我需要识别染色体组成
I need to identify the chromosomal makeup,
遗传标记
the genetic markers...
-嗯  -怎么了
- Yeah. - What? What?
你对生物遗传学  植物学有多深的了解
How extensive is your knowledge of bio-genetics? Botany?
你知道我是传染病专家
Well, you know, I'm an infectious diseases specialist.
所以你应该让我来分析这个样本
Which is why you should allow me to analyze this sample,
如果你真想知道它是什么的话
that's if you actually wanna know what it is.
亚凯恩医生
Dr. Arcane...
如果我强迫你研究我的履历...
If I forced you to study my CV--
我知道你是谁  伍德罗博士
I know who you are, Dr. Woodrue.
我还知道你为埃弗里·桑德兰工作
And I know that you're working for Avery Sunderland.
可这又有什么区别呢
But what possible difference could that make?
如果我同意的话
If I agree to this,
你必须严格保密  不能对我有任何隐瞒
I expect confidentiality and full transparency,
不管发现什么  你都要先拿给我
whatever you find, you bring to me first.
我要明白我们面对的是什么
I need to understand exactly what we're dealing with
然后才能把结果分享给全世界
before I share these results with the rest of the world.
我为什么要关心全世界
Why would I give a damn about the rest of the world?
不好意思
Excuse me.
卡西迪先生
Mr. Cassidy.
你有不止一份工作吗
Do you have a second job?
没有  我只是给孩子们带了点东西
Oh, no. I just brought in some stuff for the kids.
蓝魔鬼来查房能让他们打起精神来
They get a charge when the Blue Devil makes the rounds.
你真好
That's kind of you.
亚凯恩医生
Dr. Arcane.
我们以前见过吗
Have we met before?
我的意思是  在玛雷之前
Before Marais, I mean.
我不是故意说奇怪的话  我也说不好
I don't mean to sound weird, it's just I... I don't know,
我就是有这种感觉  就像
I got this feeling, you know? Like...
-似曾相识  -没错
- Deja vu. - Yeah.
-似曾相识  -嗯  我想
- Deja vu. - Yeah, I don't...
我想我们没见过
I don't think so.
如果见过  我一定会记得你
I'm pretty sure I would've remembered you.
-我得进去了  -好  当然
- Anyway, I have to get inside. - Right. Sure.
我应该要帮她  对吗
So I'm supposed to be helping her, right?
对吗
Right?
我问气球干什么
Why am I asking balloons?
该死
Shit.
你感觉好多了  我很高兴
I'm so happy you're feeling better.
你什么都记得  是吗
You remember everything, huh?
我还能在脑中看见他
I can still see him in my head.
我为他担心
I'm scared for him.
也为你担心
And for you.
不用担心
Don't be.
好吗
Okay?
各位  打扰一下
Excuse me, everybody.
你们感觉好多了  我和玛丽亚很高兴
Maria and I are so happy that you're all feelin' better.
为了庆祝这个好消息
To celebrate the good news,
我们邀请所有能到场的人
we are inviting everyone who is able,
来玛雷市政厅  享用传统的小龙虾盛宴
to Marais Town Hall tonight, for an old-style crawfish boil.
好啊
All right!
你们可以邀请朋友
So you can invite your friends,
邀请家人  甚至带陌生人来都行
you invite your family. Hell, bring a stranger.
我们日落时开始
We'll kick off at sunset.
该是除旧迎新
It's time to bust off the dust,
为镇子再次注入活力的时候了
and get this town movin' again.
-我马上回来  -好
- I'll be right back. - Right.
好了  亲爱的  把这个收起来吧
Okay, sweetie, let's put this away.
这就是那个在沼泽里走失的小女孩吗
Is this the little girl that was lost in the swamp?
是的  苏西·科尔
Yes. Susie Coyle.
苏西  这位是桑德兰夫人
Susie, this is Mrs. Sunderland.
你一定有别的事要忙
I'm sure you have things to do.
要不你去忙  我坐在这里陪她
Why don't you go on and I'll sit with her.
-可以吗  -嗯
- Is it okay? - Yeah.
好
All right.
你画的是什么
What have you got there?
我画了好几张的他
I drew him more.
让我看看
Show me.
艾比
Abby.
很高兴见到你  不过我也很惊讶
Good to see you, but I'm surprised.
我以为疾控中心已经收拾东西准备离开了
I thought that the CDC had packed up tent.
是的  我们已经解除危机模式了
Yeah. Well, we're out of crisis mode.
但还不能宣布"任务完成"  所以
But, uh, not ready to declare "mission accomplished" Yet, so...
我明白了
I see.
那个小女孩是在等李·科尔吗
Is that little girl, she's waiting for Lee Coyle?
是的  他现在该到了
Yeah, he should be here by now.
老李可算不上是模范市民
Well, ol' Lee is not exactly a model citizen.
我应该担心吗
Well, should I be worried?
他只是很喜欢喝酒罢了
Man knows his way around a beer bottle is all.
亚凯恩医生  有你的电话
Dr. Arcane, you have a phone call holding.
请来前台
Please come to reception.
我已经好几个月没见过玛丽亚那样笑了
I don't think I've seen Maria smile like that in months.
-我该走了  -艾比
- I... I should go. I... - Abby.
今晚见吗
I'll see you tonight?
也许吧
Maybe.
你们要告诉我发生了什么吗
You wanna tell me what all went down?
我们不知道
We don't know.
前一秒陶德还在刷锅
One minute, Todd's washing pans,
-下一秒...  -他喊着有蛇
- the next... - He's yellin' about a snake.
把手伸进了水槽粉碎机里
Puts his hand in the disposal.
是什么让一个人做出这样的事
What could make a man do something like that?
莉兹  你没事吧
Liz, you okay?
我们身体上没事  精神上就不好说了
We're all in one piece but pretty far from okay.
我会再联系你们
I'll be in touch.
有什么我能帮忙的吗
What can I do to help?
跟我解释一下  自打他穿着尿布我就认识他了
Explain to me how a kid I've known since he was in diapers
他怎么能发狂到在我爸的厨房里砍自己
could go ballistic and cut himself up in my dad's kitchen.
莉兹  这...
Liz, there are--
别和我说这事跟水里
Don't tell me it doesn't have something to do
冒出来的鬼东西无关
with that bullshit coming off the water.
你认为他从沼泽里带回了什么吗
You think he brought something back from the swamp?
这就是我打电话给你的原因
That's why I called you.
陶德去过沼泽
Todd was out there.
爆发了绿色流感
This green flu kicks up.
你的科学家朋友死而复生了
Your scientist friend coming back from the dead?
是的  但并不代表这就是一种病毒...
Yes, but that doesn't mean that can be a strain...
我们面对的可能是神经毒素
I mean, we can be looking at a neurotoxin,
线虫  还有很多其它的...
a round-worm, there are a lot of other--
那些能让他那样自残吗
That can make him tear himself up like that?
又来了
Oh, not again.
不  不
No! No!
老爸
Pops?
不
No!
老爸  怎么了
Pops, what's going on?
有人吗
Hello?
钱在哪儿
Where's the money?
天哪
Oh, God.
莉兹
Liz?
不
Oh, no.
妈妈
Mama!
抓住他
Get him.
杀了他
Kill him!
去拿钱
Get the money!
钱在哪儿
Where's the money?
离我远点
Get away from me!
杀了他妈妈
Kill the mom.
给我回来
Get back!
莉兹  莉兹
Liz! Liz!
戴尔瑞  把枪放下
Delroy, put the gun down!
将军
General.
老爸  你干什么  这里没人
Pops, what're you doing? There's nobody here!
-杀光他们  -你个混蛋
- Kill them all. - You bastards!
给我回来  回来
Get back! Get back!
你死定了  孩子
You are dead, kid.
戴尔瑞  把枪放下
Delroy, put the gun down!
回来  回来
Get back! Get back!
离我远点
Get away from me!
杀光他们
Kill them all.
回来  离她远点
Get back! Get away from her!
我看见你了  该死的
I see you, goddamn it!
戴尔瑞
Delroy!
你干什么  住手
What are you doing? Stop!
走开  快走开
Get away! Come on!
戴尔瑞  把枪放下
Delroy, put the gun down.
离我远点
Get away from me!
这里什么都没有  把枪放下
There's nothing here! Put the gun down!
这里没人
There's no one here.
莉兹  如果他不放下枪...
Lizzy, if he doesn't put the gun down...
露西莉亚  不  等等  住手
Lucilia, no! Wait! Stop!
等等  等一下
Wait! Just wait!
我会回来杀了你
I'll come back and kill you.
不  不  老爸
No! No! Pops!
住手
Stop!
莉兹
Liz.
我不能让他们伤害她
I can't let them hurt her!
你没事了
You're okay.
妈的
Son of a bitch.
戴尔瑞
Delroy.
我是凯博警长
This is Sheriff Cable.
再派一辆救护车来我的位置
I need another ambulance at my location.
收到  警长
Copy, Sheriff.
艾比  到底怎么回事
Abby, what the hell is going on?
我一直很喜欢那件蓝色的
Always liked that blue number.
这是聚会  不是火警演练  玛丽亚
It's a party. Not a fire drill, Maria.
不是强制参加的
Participation is not mandatory.
不好意思  我只是...
I'm sorry, I just...
心里一直放不下那个小女孩苏西
keep thinking about that little girl Susie and
还有她在沼泽中失去了父亲
how she lost her father in the swamp.
嗯
Yeah.
未来的生活只会更不容易
Worst part's still ahead.
你知道  我爸去世的时候
You know, I was just a little older than her when
我只比她大一点
my old man passed.
看着那个小女孩
Seeing that little girl,
一想到没有父母她要如何生活...
knowing what her life's gonna be like without her folks...
所有的记忆涌上心头
It all came back.
沼泽是如何夺走了我爸
How the swamp took my old man.
还有之后艰难的时光
The hard years after.
你自己干出了一番成就  埃弗里
You did all right for yourself, Avery.
你知道  小时候失去父亲
You know, you lose your father when you're young,
就会一辈子努力想达到他的标准
you spend your whole life trying to measure up
但大多不尽人意
and mostly comin' up short.
所以
So...
我想今天可能让我回想起了一些沉重的记忆
I mean, today brought up some old baggage for me, I guess.
你能帮我拉上拉链吗
Can you zip me up?
我很乐意
Glad to.
我很抱歉
I'm so sorry
艾比勾起了你那些不愉快的回忆  亲爱的
Abby has kicked up these ugly memories for you, honey.
埃弗里  你真贴心
That's very sweet of you, Avery.
莉兹
Lizzy?
我在这
I'm here.
告诉我  我没有伤害任何人
Tell me I didn't hurt anyone.
墙和窗户挺受伤的
The walls and windows need some love,
但人都还好
but the people are all fine.
你还记得事前发生了什么吗
Do you remember what happened right before?
突然之间  变得一片漆黑
All of a sudden, the place got dark.
就好像我踏入了一个活生生的噩梦
Like I was stepping into a living nightmare.
又是那次入室抢劫  亲爱的
It was the break-in again, sweetie.
餐馆的入室抢劫
Break-in at the Roadhouse?
我十二岁的时候  戴面具的人破门而入
When I was 12, masked men broke in.
奶奶奋起反抗  他们就当场杀了她
Grandma stood up to them. So they killed her right there.
一直没找到犯人
Never found out who did it.
多年来经常做噩梦  但是没有像这样的
Had nightmares for years but never nothin' like this.
醒着的时候没有过
Not while I was awake.
陶德昨晚告诉你们他进沼泽了
Todd told you he was in the water last night.
他有说具体地点吗
Did he tell you where?
在奥科伊河道附近
Pokin' around Ochee Forks.
肯定发生了什么
Something must've happened
因为他说他再也不要去了
because he said he was never goin' back.
好的
Okay.
好好休息
Get some rest.
好的
All right.
你在想什么
What are you thinking?
亚历克告诉我  他在沼泽能感觉到危险
Alec told me that he could sense this danger in the swamp.
从医学院开始  刻在我们脑子里的一点
I mean, one thing that was drilled into us from med school on,
就是坚持科学
is stick to science.
最终科学会给你所有答案
In the end, that's what's gonna give you answers.
但这里发生的一切
But what's going on here is...
你打算怎么做
What are you gonna do?
我打算去试试找到源头
I'm gonna go try and find the source.
这东西不管是什么
This thing, whatever it is,
是在人与人之间传播的
is being transmitted from person-to-person.
所以它肯定来自什么地方
So, it's gotta come from somewhere.
亚历克
Alec?
赫斯佩洛斯旅馆
211房间
亚历克  是你吗
Alec, is that you?
天啊
Oh, my God!
老天
Jesus.
你不该来的
You shouldn't have come.
亚历克
Alec.
你怎么知道我在这里
How did you know I was here?
我能感觉到
I felt it.
这里有一股黑暗力量
There's a darkness here.
-黑暗力量  -是的
- A darkness? - Yes.
跟这具尸体有关吗
Is it connected to this body?
曾经是的
It was.
但现在它已经被释放了
But it's been released.
昨晚两个人来到这里  其中一人
Two men came here last night and one of them was driven
因为恐惧结束了自己的生命
to take his life because of fear.
他身上可能也发生了同样的事
The same thing could've happened to him.
他死时很害怕
He died afraid.
人们发现木乃伊化的细胞组织里
Ancient viruses have been found
会有休眠的远古病毒
lying dormant in mummified tissue.
这不是疾病
It isn't a disease.
这沼泽  它
The swamp, it...
能改变东西
changes things.
如果来自尸体的有生物
If the organism that came from his body
已经在沼泽待了许多年
has been in the swamp for years,
那么它就可能还活着
then it could still be out there.
黑暗力量总是要找新的宿主
The darkness always seeks a new host.
另一个受害人
Another victim.
另一个宿主
Another host.
陶德抓伤了戴尔瑞  然后戴尔瑞
Todd scratched Delroy, and Delroy...
天哪  露西莉亚可能被感染了
Oh, my God. Lucilia could be infected.
抱歉  我得回玛雷了
I'm sorry. Look, I have to get back to Marais.
艾比
Abby.
这个东西
This... thing...
属于沼泽
belongs here in the swamp.
大家准备好享乐了吗
Everybody ready to have a good time?
我做的怎么样
How'd I do?
你总是很擅长提醒人们
Oh, you're always good at reminding people
你为他们做的一切
all you've done for them.
让人们知道是谁给面包抹了黄油比较好
Always nice to let people know who's buttering the bread,
或者应该说是小龙虾
or the. crawfish as the case may be.
苏西·科尔怎么在这
What's Susie Coyle doing here?
我觉得她也许会很喜欢的
Oh, I thought she might enjoy it.
她叔叔的情况不是很好
Her uncle's been having a hard time,
我们也许会收留
and I said we might take little Susie
小苏西一段时间
for a night or a couple of days.
-我知道我应该  -不  听起来不错
- I know I should've- - No, no, it sounds good.
你好  苏西
Hello. Hello, Susie.
你已经见过娜丁了
I see you've met Nadine.
我们去拿些吃的吧
Why don't we grab some food?
在那边有个房间  我们可以互相了解熟悉
I've got a room over there. We'll all get acquainted.
-你觉得怎么样  小苏西  -好
- What do you say, little Susie? - Yeah.
好的
Okay.
丹尼尔
Daniel.
你怎么知道是我
How did you know it was me?
你想要什么
What is it you want?
你还有看到其它什么的吗
Have you seen anything more?
任何关于我使命的内容
About my... mission, whatever it is?
我很忙
I've been busy.
别这样  上都夫人
Come on, Ms. X.
试一下  也许你会有灵感的
You just try, maybe you get a hint.
实话实说  丹尼尔
The truth is, Daniel,
卡牌目前并不明朗
the cards aren't clear right now.
并不只是你的
Not just about you.
整个镇子的未来都不明朗
About the future of this entire town.
什么
What?
你是说你失去天赋了吗
Are you saying you lost your gift?
我只知道
All I know now is...
风暴要来临了  丹尼尔
a storm is coming, Daniel.
有大事要发生
Something big.
会影响到整个镇子
Something that will affect the destiny of this entire town,
和这里所有人的命运
and everyone in it.
可怕的事情要来了
Something terrible is coming.
然后在这时我的卡牌变化了
And this is when my cards change?
八年前当我第一次来玛雷时
Eight years ago, when you'd first come to Marais,
你和我说你做了笔交易
you told me you'd made a bargain.
除非被召唤  你会永远和这个镇子绑在一起
One that bound you to this town until called upon.
是的
Right.
不管是什么灾难来临的时候
When the shit comes down, whatever it is,
你会在这里帮忙的  对吗
you're gonna be here to help, right?
如果我能帮的话
If I can.
但你已经被命运召唤了
But you've been called to a destiny.
每个英雄的路都只能独自走下去
Every hero's path is theirs to walk alone.
回声周报
1923年的今天
赫斯佩洛斯旅馆五人死亡
我不敢相信你打来了
I couldn't believe your call.
你认为下一个是露西莉亚
You think Lucilia's next?
我看到戴尔瑞抓伤她了
I saw Delroy scratch her.
而它就是这样传播的  莉兹
And that's how it's transmitted, Liz,
通过血液从感染者传播到下一个人
from one infected person to the next through blood.
这和我之前见过的都不一样
It's... It's nothing like I've ever seen before. I...
那把钥匙上的名字有什么含义吗
Did the name on that key mean anything?
《回声周报》刊登过一篇
The Echo did a retrospective
关于1930年的玛雷镇的报导
on 1930's Marais a while back.
赫斯佩洛斯旅馆是本地的家庭旅馆
The Hotel Esperos was a local boarding house.
那里发生了很奇怪的事
And some very strange shit went down there.
赫斯佩洛斯旅馆五人死亡
什么
What?
第一次出事的是个一战老兵
The first incident was a World War I vet.
他在自己的船上胡言乱语  说洞要塌了
They found him on his boat raving about dirt caving in on him,
仿佛他回到了战壕里
like he was back in the trenches.
沉浸于自己的噩梦中
Like his own personal nightmare.
他回到旅馆之后  当地人报警说
After he came back to the hotel, locals reported
听到了尖叫声还看见了奇怪的行为
hearing screams and seeing strange behavior.
但病传播的太快了
But it was spreading so fast
当局束手无策
the authorities had no clue what to do.
那他当时一定传染给了别人
So he must've passed it on to someone else,
然后就一个接一个传下去了
and then it just went from person to person.
什么时候停止的
When did it stop?
最后一个受害者发疯然后消失了
The last victim just flipped out and vanished.
几周后  他们在奥科伊河道发现了他的船
Weeks later, they found his boat drifting near Ochee Forks.
他可能知道自己被感染了
I wonder if he knew he had the infection.
所以他去了沼泽里自杀
So he went to the swamp and killed himself
这样就把病传染给别人
so he wouldn't pass it on to anyone else.
直到陶德出现了
Until Todd came along.
你又来巡逻了  妈
You working the room, Ma?
你怎么就不能好好享受一下呢
Why can't you ever just enjoy yourself, hmm?
那就是原因
That's the reason why.
我来处理
I'll take care of it.
别闹了
Knock it off!
干掉他
Get him.
马特
Matt!
马特  不
Matty! No!
警员受伤  需要救护车
10-33, officer down! I need an ambulance!
孩子  妈妈不许你死
Oh, baby don't! No! Mama says no!
马特  看着我  看着我
Matty! Look at me. Look at me.
马特
Matty!
睁开眼睛
Open your eyes!
不
No!
马特
Matty!
马特  坚持住
Matty, stay with me.
马特
Matty!
露西莉亚
Lucilia!
退后
Stay back!
-露西莉亚  -退后
- Lucilia! - Stay back!
别过来
Stay away!
没事了
It's okay.
-退后  -露西莉亚  听我说
- Stay back! - Lucilia! Listen to me!
退后  我要一枪
Stay back! I will blast that fucking smile
打爆你的头
right off your fucking face!
这不是真的  这不是真的
It's not real. It's not real!
-退后  -露西莉亚
- Stay back! - Lucilia!
马特没事
Matty is okay.
露西莉亚  看着我  这不是真的
Lucilia, look at me! Look at me! This is not real!
-别过来  -这不是真的
- Get away! - This is not real!
你生病了  你要和我一起走
You're sick. You have to come with me.
-不  放开我  -你要跟我走  露西莉亚
- No! Get off of me! - Lucilia! You have to come with me!
-放开我  -你要跟我走  露西莉亚
- Get off of me! - You have to come with me! Lucilia!
马特
Matty.
Matty...
是我  没事了
It's me. It's okay.
-快点  医生  我们得离开这里  -不  不
- Come on, Doc, we gotta get out of here. - No, no!
-我试着阻止他  -我就在这
- I tried to stop him. - I'm right here.
-宝贝  -马特
- Baby. - Matt!
送她去医院
Get her to the hospital.
好  好  来吧
Yeah. Yeah. Come on.
艾比
Abby!
莉兹  别碰我
Liz! Don't touch me!
它在我体内  那东西在我身体里
It's in me. That thing is in me.
我得把它带回沼泽
I have to take it back to the swamp.
亚历克
Alec?
Alec!
亚历克
Alec?
艾比
Abby...
我一直在等待
I've been waiting.
你妈妈想把你从我身边夺走
Your mommy tried to take you from me,
但我仍存在于你的梦中
but I'm still in your dreams.
你以为她死后就会结束了
You thought they ended when she died.
我就永远消失了
That I was gone forever!
但你仍然还是那个害怕的小女孩
But you are still just a scared little girl,
试图逃避过去
trying to hide from your past.
别抵抗了
Don't fight it!
你妈妈想见你
Your mother wants to see you.
你想了解黑暗
You wanted to understand the darkness.
我会让你见识到的
I'll show you!
艾比
Abby!
我帮你把它拿走
Let me take this from you.
亚历克
Alec!
Alec...
你在做什么
What are you doing?
他为保护他所爱之人而死
He died to protect the ones he loved.
黑暗不应该离开他的
The darkness was never meant to leave him.
他把它收回去了
He took it back.
现在这个地方吸收了他
And now this place has taken him.
我不明白  你怎么知道所有这些的
I don't understand. How do you know all of this?
植物  树木
The plants, the trees...
我想他们在和我说话
I think they're talking to me.
玛丽亚  我刚挂断电话
Maria, I just got off the phone.
看来我们的警长是严重的食物中毒
Seems our sheriff came down with a bad case of food poisoning.
高烧
High fever.
马特带她一起走了
She went off with Matt.
去让医生看一下
To have the doctors take a look.
她在这里挺高兴的
She seems happy here.
家里又有孩子了  感觉挺好的  对吗
It'd be nice... to have a child in the house again, huh?
你知道
You know...
我在想
I was thinking...
她叔叔和婶婶已经有四个孩子了
Her uncle and his wife already have four kids of their own.
再加一个他们恐怕力不从心
Taking another one on would stretch them pretty thin.
你在想她应该留在这里
You're thinking she should stay here?
我可以问问
I could ask.
我只希望上帝保佑她没事
I just hope to God she's okay.
我觉得疾控中心离开得太仓促了
You know, the CDC raced out of here pretty quick in my opinion.
-好吧  如果我有...  -他们留下了艾比
- Well, if I had-- - They left Abby.
他们显然没搞清楚这种绿色流感
Clearly they don't understand this green flu.
所以我才一直给伍德罗博士钱
That's why I'm keeping Dr. Woodrue on the payroll.
只能他能找到真正的治愈方法
He's the only person who could find a real cure for this thing,
确保她没事
make sure she's okay.
我的意思是
Oh, what I mean...
她一定会没事的
I'm sure that she is gonna be fine.
苏西怎么样了
How's Susie?
你真的在乎吗  科尔
What do you care, Coyle?
这可以兑现
It's made out to cash.
最好去城里找个大点的银行
Better take it to a big bank in the city.
这到底是要干什么  桑德兰
So what's this really about, Sunderland?
这样买一个孩子
Buying a kid like this?
你不爱那个小女孩
You don't love that little girl.
你知道那些请求捐赠帮助那些
You know those commercials that they run asking for donations,
外国挨饿的可怜孩子的广告吧
to help some poor starving child overseas?
广播上没有这种广告是有原因的
There's a reason they don't put those on the radio.
如果你希望人们慷慨解囊
See, if you want people to pony up,
就必须让他们看到那些生病的可怜孤儿
they have to see those sad, sick orphans,
这样才能打开他们的支票簿
in order to open their checkbooks.
伍德罗博士将会得到他所需的一切
And Dr. Woodrue is gonna get everything he needs
来保证小苏西不会有事
to make sure little Susie is all right.
祝你晚安  李
Hey, you have a good night, Lee.
别在酒吧里花光了
Don't spend it all in a bar.
我不会放弃你的
I'm not giving up on you.
我会找到答案的
I'm going to find an answer.
黑暗
The darkness...
让你害怕
made you afraid.
你看到了什么
What did you see?
我看到了一些我以为已经忘记的东西
I saw something I thought I'd forgotten.
我小时候
When I was a little girl,
几乎每天晚上都会哭着醒来
I would wake up crying almost every night,
害怕这...
scared that this, uh...
这个没有脸的怪物会来
This faceless monster was gonna come
把我从我母亲身边夺走
and tear me away from my mother.
她死后  噩梦就停止了
When she died, the nightmares stopped.
但是小时候  那...那感觉非常真实
But when I was little, it was, uh... it was very real.
我是一名医生  亚历克  你是生物学家  我
I'm a doctor, Alec. You are a biologist. I...
告诉我这一切怎么解释得通
Tell me how any of this makes sense.
解释不通
It doesn't.
没法用我们以前理解的方式来解释
Not in any way that we used to understand.
那这黑暗
So this darkness...
到底是从哪里来的
Where does it come from?
这片沼泽被污染了
The swamp's been polluted.
被下毒了
Poisoned.
当平衡遭到破坏  生灵遭受折磨
And when the balance shifts, life suffers,
-黑暗便会降临  -带来死亡
- and darkness finds release... - ...bringing death.
是的
Yes.
我怎么会明白这些
How am I seeing these things?
我已经不知道我是谁了  艾比
I don't know who I am anymore, Abby.
你是亚历克·霍兰
You're Alec Holland.
你是我的朋友
You're my friend.
我为你担心  艾比
I'm scared for you, Abby.
一切才刚刚开始
This is only the beginning.